我说什么傻话了吗
Did I say anything stupid?
我就喝了两杯
I had two drinks.
三杯
Three.
好吧  那最后一杯也算上
Okay. Yeah. There was that last one also.
没关系  如果某一天你也怀孕的话
It's okay. Someday you'll be pregnant,
你就可以回报我啦
and you can return the favor.
我有时感觉自己像个傻瓜
I feel like such a idiot sometimes.
有了孩子后  我就
You know, when the baby comes, I am gonna be--
知道吗  你会是个很棒的父亲
You know what? You're gonna be so great.
你会的
You are.
你还好吗
You all right?
糟糕
Oh, no.
知道为什么我让你们靠边停吗
You know why I pulled you over?
我  我很抱歉  警官
I'm-- I'm so sorry, Officer.
我一定是...瞌睡了
I must have, uh, dozed off.
你喝酒了吗
Have you been drinking?
-没有  -她当然没喝
- No. - Of course she hasn't.
-有人喝了  -我刚喝了点酒
- Somebody has.  - I've been drinking.
-你还好吗  -我  我
- You all right? - Uh, I'm-- I'm-- I'm not, uh--
-你们开了多远  -差不多
- How far along are you? - Uh, almost--
女士  请下车
Ma'am, step out of the vehicle.
女士  走到汽车尾部
Ma'am, walk to the rear of the car.
内奥米  你
Naomi. Are--
内奥米
Naomi?
-内奥米  -先生  请待在车里
- Naomi. - Sir, remain in the car.
嘿  听着  她没喝酒
Hey, listen. She's not drunk.
先生  我会逮捕你的
I will arrest you, sir.
-她病了  你们看到吗  -你再靠近我试试
- She's sick! Look at her. - Can you roll me another unit?
回到车里
Get back in the car.
内奥米
Naomi!
走开
Get off.
叫救护车
Call an ambulance.
好消息是这看来不像是中风
The good news is it doesn't look like a stroke.
没内出血也没有血栓
No bleeds, no clots.
-谢天谢地  -但好像还有坏消息
- Thank God.  - It sounds like there's bad news.
你的血检结果出来了
We got your blood work back.
某些指数不正常
Some things are a little off.
说明你的肝和肾可能出了些问题
Your liver and kidneys aren't working so well.
为什么  那是什么造成的呢
Why? What would cause that?
是子痫前期吗
It's preeclampsia, isn't it?
我会流产  对吗
I'm gonna miscarry, aren't I?
子痫前期是种可能
Preeclampsia is a possibility.
但先别太早下结论
But let's not get ahead of ourselves.
我已经流产三次了  我39岁
I've miscarried three times. I'm 39.
我们不得不采用体外受精
We had to use in vitro.
你必须得保证孩子没事
You've gotta make sure the baby's okay.
先确保你没事
Let's make sure that you're okay first.
我们何不同时照料好你们俩呢
How about we take care of both of you at the same time?
护士很快会来抽取一些血样
The nurse will be in soon to take some blood.
我要多做几项检查
I'd like to run some more tests.
-多谢你  医生  -多谢
- Thank you, Doctor. - Thank you.
-人都哪儿去了  -办公室里没人吗
- Where is everybody? - No one's in the office?
没有  一整天都没见到卡梅隆
No. I haven't heard from Cameron all day.
你见到豪斯了吗
You seen House?
去沃格勒看守的浅坟里找找吧
Look for a shallow grave with Vogler standing over it.
你的癌症已经是末期了
You have a stage IV cancer.
现在已经转移至肝脏
It's metastasized to your liver.
有一种新药叫做8C12
There's a new drug called 8C12
临床二期效果显著
that's shown promise in Phase II trials.
这是你最好的机会了
It's your best shot.
多谢  医生
Thank you, Doctor.
你一直都对我很好可我
You've been so good to me and--
恩  我  我
Well, I-- I did...
公开批评贵公司的药剂
publicly bash your company's drug.
我一想到对你的种种
When I think about how I treated you--
哦  嘿  算了吧
Oh, hey. Come on.
别这样  会好的
There, there, there.
那么说  还是有希望的了
So, um, there is some hope.
总会有的
Always.
但只是以防万一
But just in case,
我特别为你订制了一个超大尺寸的棺材
I special-ordered an extra-jumbo-sized coffin.
别谢我  我就是这样的好人
Don't thank me. It's just who I am.
起来干活儿了  小伙
Up and at 'em, big guy.
抱歉  昨晚熬夜看网络黄片了
Sorry. Up late. Internet porn.
你怎么不在办公室睡呢
How come you're not in your office?
因为办公室里有电脑
Because there is a computer in my office,
我一登录上  情节就又继续了
and if I log on, romance will ensue.
我的腕关节可支持不了多久
My wrist might fall off.
藏起来是因为沃格勒在找你  对吧
Hiding 'cause Vogler's looking for you, huh?
实在是可悲
That's just pathetic.
我不喜欢聒噪愤怒的大块头
I don't like loud, angry giants
使用暴力威胁我
threatening me with violence.
这有什么可悲的
How is that pathetic?
你觉得躲在这就不用开除我们中的一个了
You think you can avoid firing one of us by hiding out here?
他早晚会找到你的
He'll find you sooner or later.
那就让他晚点找到我吧
I'm okay with later.
女性  39岁  怀孕28周
39-year-old female, 28 weeks pregnant.
血糖值4  血蛋白值0
G, four. P, zero.
三次流产
Three miscarriages?
给我
Gimme.
精神状态不稳定而且整体协调性缺失
Altered mental status and complete loss of coordination.
毒理检验结果呢
Tox screen?
酒精和毒品检测呈阴性
Negative for alcohol and drugs.
-她在服用奥昔布宁  -治疗失禁
- She was on oxybutynin.  - For incontinence.
是的  不过已经停用  没变化
Yeah. Well, we took her off. No change.
血尿素氮和肌酸酐值都很高
B.U.N. And creatinine are up.
肝功指数也有点升高
L.F.T.'s slightly elevated.
子痫前期
Preeclampsia.
送去妇产科  然后祈祷吧
Call the OB-GYN service and rub some prayer beads.
血压正常  前几次怀孕没出现子痫前期
B.P.'s normal. No preeclampsia in other pregnancies.
因为她没能怀孕那么长时间
Because she didn't carry for long enough.
三次流产
The three miscarriages
我觉得可能是潜在身体机能问题
make me think it's an underlying physiology.
妊娠相关自身免疫
Pregnancy-related autoimmunity.
真不巧卡梅隆辞职了
Too bad that Cameron quit.
不然就有免疫学专家了
We could use an immunologist right now.
我们来看看你说的对不对  检查血样
We'll see if you're right. Check the blood.
卡梅隆辞职了
Cameron quit?
昨晚
Last night.
再做一个磁共振血管成像检查血管炎
And do an M.R.A. for vasculitis too.
她不可能辞职
There's no way she quit.
她是被开除的  因为你不愿意忍气吞声
She got fired because you couldn't swallow your pride.
做个超声检查  好主意
An ultrasound? Excellent thought.
再给她服点镁防止子痫前期发作
And put her on magnesium too, in case it is preeclampsia.
好的
Sure.
嗟  来食...
Here, pussy, pussy, pussy.
-我什么都没做  -就是我想说的
- I didn't do anything. - Exactly my point.
你想让我冲他吼吗
You wanted me to yell at him?
那又能怎么样
What would that have achieved?
难道他能跳进时间机器
Was he gonna jump into his time machine
回到过去弥补一切吗
and fix everything?
假如你家狗拉在地板上了
When a dog dumps on the floor,
你会去拍拍它的头吗
do you pat its head?
不  你会用报纸狠抽它
No. You smack it in the nose with a newspaper.
狗知错就改  豪斯可不会
Dogs can learn things. House can't.
-懦夫  -幼稚
- Coward. - Child.
嘿  你们好
Hey, there.
我带同事来帮忙检查
I, uh, brought my colleague along to help out.
你们好  我是奇斯医生
Hi. I'm Dr. Chase.
你好
Hi.
超声图像看来正常
Well, ultrasound looks good.
没有胎儿窘迫迹象
No sign of fetal distress.
那不是子痫前期
So it's not preeclampsia?
还是有可能的  但至少目前没有恶化
Well, it still could be, but it hasn't progressed at least.
请你平躺休息  我们要监测孩子的状况
We're gonna put you on bed rest and monitor the baby.
好的
Okay.
同时要给你补充一些钾和镁
We'll give you some potassium and magnesium as well.
现在就给她持续输液
We should keep the fluids running for now...
一个小时后再来检查
and check her again in an hour
-万一出现有胎儿窘迫再说  -亲爱的
- unless there are signs of fetal distress. - Honey?
她噎到了
She's choking!
身体前倾
Lean forward.
-她怎么了  -可能是有些肌无力
- Is she all right? - Probably just some muscle weakness.
-什么叫"可能"  -内奥米  张嘴
- What do you mean "Probably"? - Naomi, open up.
人吃东西都会噎到的  可能没什么
People choke. It could be nothing.
你还好吗
You all right?
我不能  我不能吞咽了
I can't-- I can't-- I can't even swallow.
她经常生病
She gets sick a lot.
就像这样  这次感冒突然就变得很严重
Like this-- this cold got really bad all of a sudden.
还发烧
And the fever--
嘘  没事的
Shh. It's okay.
不是感冒  是肺炎
It's not a cold. It's pneumonia.
肺炎
Pneumonia?
别紧张  肺炎只是她的第二大问题
Relax. Pneumonia's her second biggest problem.
她的体重本来重于25%的同龄儿
She has gone from the 25th weight percentile
结果一个月内成了最轻的那3%
to the third in one month.
我不是婴儿方面专家
I'm not a baby expert,
但我肯定婴儿不应该缩小
but I'm pretty sure they're not supposed to shrink.
在她停止母乳喂养后
Well, there's this diet we put her on
我们给她规定了饮食
when she stopped breast-feeding.
是健康的方式  生食  我们是素食者
But it's healthy. Um, raw food. We're vegans.
杏仁牛奶  豆腐  蔬菜
Almond milk, tofu, uh, vegetables.
生食
Raw food.
要是祖先们会生火就好了
If only her ancestors had mastered the secret of fire.
婴孩需要脂肪  蛋白质  热量
Babies need fat, proteins, calories.
其次才是豆芽和纤维
Less important, sprouts and hemp.
让孩子受饿可不好
Starving babies is bad--
在一些国家甚至犯法的
and illegal in many cultures.
帮她办住院手续吧
I'm having her admitted.
她会好起来吗
Is she gonna be all right?
用抗生素治疗肺炎
Antibiotics for the pneumonia,
静脉营养疗法恢复她的体重
I.V. feeding to get the weight up.
别担心  静脉注射的是素食
Don't worry. It's a vegan I.V.
成像显示无任何血管炎迹象
Don't see any signs of vasculitis.
奇怪
Odd.
你不是什么事情总是对的嘛
Since you're always right about everything.
也许是不同的自身免疫症
Could be a different autoimmunity.
或者驳倒我
Or you could bite me.
哦  不
Oh, no.
内奥米  你还好吗
Naomi, you okay?
不好  我不能  我肚子好疼
No. I can't-- I'm getting cramps.
-厉害吗  -是的  就好像要流产
- Strong? - Oh. Yeah. Feels like my miscarriage.
-停下  -要早产了
- Stop. - Preterm labor.
他还太小  肯定活不下来的
He's too little. He won't survive.
-她已经服过镁了  -注射间羟舒喘宁
- She's on magnesium already.  - Fluids and terbutaline then.
我们得给你服一些药  好吗
We're gonna give you some medicine,okay?
-阻止你的分娩  -好的
- Try to stop your labor. - Okay.
好的
Okay.
你在这儿啊  我到处找你
There you are. Been looking everywhere for you.
哦  对了
Uh, listen,
你说过如果我不对你的新药好好评价的话
you said that I had to cut one of my people...
我就得开除一个人
if I didn't give that speech about your drug.
凭良心说吧
And, uh, in fairness to your point of view,
我的评论真不合你意
my speech really wasn't the one you had in mind
所以我开了卡梅隆
so I've cut Cameron.
现在你我两清了吧
Now we're all squared away, right?
明天早上  我希望看到你
In the morning, I expect you...
拿着你的辞职信到我办公室来
in my office with your letter of resignation...
并且准备公开道歉
and plans for a public apology,
否则我会彻底打垮你
otherwise I'll destroy you.
所以你是说我们还没扯平
So, that's a no on us being squared away?
她也许能捱到胎儿足月
She might make it to full term.
宫缩次数正在减少而且不那么明显了
Contractions are less frequent and not well organized.
真高兴看见你回到这里
Great to see you back in the office.
沃格勒找到你了吧
I guess Vogler found you?
是啊  我们和气地聊了一会儿
Yeah. We had a nice little chat.
我真应该留下卡梅隆
I really should have kept Cameron.
她知道糖放在哪儿
She knew where to find the sugar.
就是我说的  子痫前期
It's what I said: preeclampsia.
她躺在造影机里有点紧张
A little stress from the M.R.A.,
所以造成早产
she pops right into labor.
会不会是肌无力
What about the myasthenia?
算了  她看上去没那么虚弱
Come on. She didn't seem that weak.
可她确实噎住了  甚至无法吞咽
She choked. She couldn't even swallow.
-什么东西把她噎住了  -吃的东西
- What did she choke on? - Her food.
但是肌无力不是子痫前期的症状
But muscle weakness isn't a symptom of preeclampsia.
-什么吃的东西  -一点熟梨片
- What kind of food? - A little bit of cooked pear.
无关紧要  她就是身体虚弱了点
Doesn't matter. Shows weakness.
嫩滑的梨片就能把她噎住了
She choked on soft, wet pear?
吃梨还要吐骨头吗
Did she forget to take the bones out?
她也太无力了吧
That's way past muscle weakness.
有没有给她做内窥镜检查
Did you do an upper endoscopy?
你觉得她食管里有东西堵着
You think there's something obstructing her esophagus?
-我们得谈谈  -唔  我们得谈谈了
- We gotta talk. - Ooh. We gotta talk.
还有  检查她的眼睑
And check her eyelids.
检查眼睑
Check her eyelids?
今天董事会要开特别会议
Special board meeting today.
只有一个议题  你
Only one item on the agenda: you.
会上多吃点百吉饼  谁也动不了我
Enjoy the bagels. I'm untouchable.
你厉害
Right.
任何撤销我任期的表决必须全票通过才能生效
Any vote to revoke my tenure has to be unanimous.
我有你保我  说不定还有卡迪
I've got you and maybe even Cuddy.
是啊  这就能摆平他了
Well, that settles it.
无情的企业狙击手先生[公司蓄意收购者]
Mr. Ruthless Corporate Raider...
会被我们击溃  跑回家
will be totally stymied, go home,
蜷缩在地板上  淹没在泪海中
curl up on the floor of his shower and weep.
他能怎么办  我是签了合同的
What can he do? I got a contract.
你的合同写没写付多少薪水给你的团队
Does it say how much your team is paid,
你的停车位在哪里
where you parking space is,
你的车是不是该塞满马粪
if your car should be filled with horse manure?
沃格勒是个聪明人
Vogler's smart.
他肯定已经想好怎么对付你了
He's got some plan to get you.
会对我用糖衣炮弹吗
Does it involve candy?
因为我对巧克力毫无免疫力
'Cause I'm a sucker for chocolates.
-她好多了  -感谢上帝
- She's doing better. - Oh, thank God.
准确来讲  要感谢亚历山大·弗莱明
Technically, Alexander Fleming.
他发明了抗生素
He developed antibiotics.
肺炎已经控制住了
Pneumonia's under control.
从现在起  给她吃人吃的东西  可以吗
From now on, what say you go with human food, okay?
-绝对  向上帝发誓  -这次你找对人了
- Absolutely. Swear to God. - This time, that's your guy.
是瑞秋和乔·卡普兰吗
Rachel and Joel Kaplan?
-是的  -你们被捕了
- Yes? - You're under arrest.
-你们有权保持沉默  -我们犯什么法了
- You have the right to remain silent. - What did we do?
你们被指控迫害儿童
You're being charged with child endangerment.
什么  怎么回事
What? How?
让你们的孩子挨饿  我是社会福利部的
Starving your kid. I'm from Social Services.
现在起你们的孩子由我们照顾
We're taking responsibility for your baby.
这就是沃格勒击垮我的手段吗
This is how Vogler's gonna destroy me?
他干什么了  给你的拐棍儿抹油
What did he do? Grease your cane?
他找人抓走了我的病人
He had my patients arrested.
错了  不是他  是我
Uh, no. He didn't. I did.
护士们为那孩子担心  给我打来了电话
The nurses were concerned, and they called me.
明明有虐待的迹象
There was evidence of abuse.
却不上报社会福利部  你这是在冒法律风险
You took a big legal risk by not calling Social Services.
那对父母又不是虐待狂  就是白痴了点
Those parents are not abusive. They're idiots.
哟  那还真是松了一口气
Oh, well, that's certainly a relief.
-这件事该由我作主  -你做错了
- It was my call. - You made the wrong one.
你知道吗  最近出了本"昆斯林新传"
You know, there's a new biography of Quisling.
Quisling[二战时挪威政治家  曾与纳粹合作
卖国贼的代名词]
我想你会喜欢的
I think you might like it.
当然  那是谁
Sure. No idea who that is.
是个挪威人  二战时期做了卖国贼
Uh, Norwegian guy, World War II, traitor.
跟你解释这个都灭了我的火
The fact that I have to explain this takes the edge off my flow.
我是在保护你
I was protecting you.
保护我什么  警察根本不会抓我
From what? Cops aren't gonna bust me.
纪律委员会顶多警告一下我
Disciplinary Committee maybe gives me a slap on the wrist.
于是沃格勒就有理由开了你
And Vogler has an excuse to get rid of you.
欲加之罪  何患无辞
If I don't give him one, he makes one up.
沃格勒一个人只有一票
Vogler's just one vote.
他要想办法说服其他11个董事
He's gotta convince the other 11 of us.
我只是在阻止你让这事变得超级简单
I'm just trying to stop you from making that extra easy.
[查尔斯医生  请回电4541]
Dr. Charles, dial 4541.
肖恩  你妻子的眼睑看起来
Sean, do your wife's eyelids
跟平时有什么不一样吗
look any different than usual?
好像一边有点下垂
Uh, maybe one is drooping a little bit,
但是  她很累了  所以说...
but, you know, she's tired, so--
内奥米  请你张开嘴
Naomi, can you open your mouth for me and,
头向后仰
um, tilt your head back?
这会有点不舒服
This is gonna be a little uncomfortable.
果然  有肿胀阻塞了食道
Yeah. There's swelling, indenting the esophagus.
所以她才会被噎住的吗
Is that why she choked?
需要照个X光片
We'll need to do an X-ray.
什么  不行  我的孩子
What? No. The baby.
你说过我不能照X光
You said no X-rays.
必须得照
It's important.
她的右肺叶上部
She has a three-centimeter mass...
有一块三厘米大小的阴影
in her right upper lobe.
-可能是肉芽肿  -不是
- Maybe it's a granuloma. - No.
没有钙化
There's no calcification.
是小细胞肺癌
It's small-cell lung cancer.
肿瘤开始压迫你的食道了
The tumor's starting to press against your esophagus.
癌细胞还没有转移
It hasn't metastasized,
但是已经扩散到肺部其它地方
but it has spread to other parts of your lung,
所以我们没法手术
so we can't operate.
等等  这讲不通啊
Wait. That doesn't make sense.
她之前  还有肾衰和脑部的问题
She had, uh, kidney failure and brain problems.
一些癌症病人会出现
Some cancer patients get
叫作副肿瘤综合征的情况
what are called paraneoplastic syndromes.
你的体内产生抗体抗击癌细胞
You were making antibodies to fight the tumor.
但是它们转而攻击其它细胞
They got sidetracked and attacked other cells.
先是你的大脑  然后是肝  肾
Your brain first. Then your liver, kidneys.
甚至是控制你眼睑的神经
Even the nerves that control your eyelids.
这个叫兰伯特-伊顿综合征
That's called Lambert-Eaton syndrome.
我们由此想到肿瘤在肺里
It told us the tumor was in the lungs.
有多糟
How bad is it?
小细胞肺癌是肺癌中恶变最快的
Small-cell is the most aggressive kind of lung cancer.
五年存活率只有百分之十到十五
The five-year survival rate is only about 10% to 15%.
所以我们必须
Which is why we have to
马上对你进行化疗和放疗
start you on chemo and radiation right away.
放疗  我的孩子怎么办
Radiation? What about the baby?
开始治疗之前需要给你剖腹产
You'll need a C-section before you can start the treatment.
我可以为你安排明天一早做手术
I can get you in first thing tomorrow morning.
我孩子活下来的希望有多大
What are the chances my baby will survive?
很乐观
Pretty good.
现在二十八周了  应该有百分之八十
Twenty-eight weeks, so about 80%.
不  等等  也就是说有两成可能会死
No, wait. That's one-in-five chance he'll die?
我真的不建议你再等下去
I really wouldn't advise waiting.
内奥米  你必须马上开始治疗
Naomi, you gotta start this treatment right away
如果我再等等会怎么样
What happens if I wait?
二十九周
Well, 29 weeks,
存活率会接近百分之九十
the survival rate is closer to 90%.
-那我现在不做放疗  -可你会死的...
- I'm not doing the radiation. - But you'll die if--
听我说  你也看到了  我肯定活不成
Listen. You know the chances. They're nothing.
但是再多等几周就能保住孩子
But a few more weeks will save the baby.
听着  你现在心里很难过
Listen. You're depressed right now,
头脑不够清醒  所以...
and you're not thinking right, so--
能不能请你  请你劝劝她吧
Could you j-- Tell her, please.
这种癌症扩散非常快
This cancer moves quick.
到了中期你就只能活两到四个月了
The median survival's two to four months.
如果你推迟治疗  哪怕是一周...
If you postpone-- even for a week--
对不起  亲爱的
I'm sorry, honey.
众所周知
As most of you know,
格利高里·豪斯最近发表了一番关于我的言论
Gregory House recently gave a speech about me.
本着礼尚往来的精神
I'd like to return the favor.
-抱歉  -威尔森医生
- Sorry. - Dr. Wilson.
我是希望你会错过这次会议
I was hoping you were gonna miss this one.
一个人行为体现其人格
A man is the sum of his actions.
下面是豪斯医生的若干行为
Here are a few of Dr. House's.
他曾违反放弃抢救协议
He violated a D.N.R.
并被指控伤害他人
and was charged with assault.
他把白蚁带进了手术室
He brought a termite into the O.R.
与外科医生发生争吵
and spat on a surgeon.
他接受了病人送的名车
He accepted a Corvette from a patient
而此人已知是新泽西州黑手党成员
who was a known member of the New Jersey Mafia.
-爱德  我说...  -是爱德华
- Ed, look-- - Edward.
爱德华
Edward.
如果你探查任意一个人的职业生涯
You look at anyone's career,
你都能发现一些事情是...
you can find things that are--
这些只是他前三个月的罪状
These are the last three months.
他个人所遭到的投诉
He's personally had more complaints
比这家医院任何一个部门都要多
filed against him than any department in this hospital.
没错  他这人是一团糟  是惹人生厌
Okay. He's screwed-up. He's miserable.
也许他应该去重新读读职业道德规范
And he should probably reread the ethics code,
但这就是他的方式  他救了几百条人命
but it works for him. He's saved hundreds of lives.
他嗜药成瘾  不仅以此为荣
He is a drug addict who flaunts his addiction
还拒绝治疗
and refuses to get treatment.
他是本院的耻辱  令我们蒙羞
He is a disgrace and an embarrassment to this hospital.
我本可继续  但这么讲下去有失身份  所以
I'd go on, but it gets kind of mean, so--
我简单说
I'm gonna keep this simple.
豪斯走还是我走
House goes or I go.
不要公私不分
You shouldn't personalize this.
我说的"我"  是指我的亿万美金
And by "I", I mean my hundred million dollars.
这叫公私不分吗
How's that for personalizing?
你给我们钱是有所为的
You gave us that money for a reason.
你真的愿意因为一个医生
Are you really willing to throw it all away
而放弃你的初衷吗
because of one doctor?
豪斯是医疗保健业的一个反面教材
Gregory House is a symboy of everything wrong with the health care industry.
浪费  不服从上级
Waste. Insubordination.
医生们个个趾高气昂  自以为王
Doctors preening like they're kings,
医院俨然成了他们的私人封地
and the hospital is their own private fiefdom.
医疗保健业是一桩生意
Health care is a business.
我要把它经营得像个样子
I'm gonna run it like one.
现在我提议将格利高里·豪斯医生撤职
I here by move to revoke the tenure of Dr. Gregory House...
并终止其与本院的雇佣关系
and terminate his employment at this hospital,
即刻生效
effective immediately.
我们是不是应该先讨论一下
Don't you think we should discuss this?
我们刚刚讨论过了
We just did.
我们需要时间...
We need time--
现在公开表决  是否都赞成
The vote is on the table. All in favor?
-威尔森医生  -反对
- Dr. Wilson. - Opposed.
提案未通过
The motion is defeated.
威尔森医生  请你离开会议室  好吗
Dr. Wilson, would you mind leaving the room, please?
-你说什么  -我们要进行另一项表决
- Excuse me? - We're going to take another vote.
首先  你不能通过驱赶我出去
Well, first of all, you can't void my vote
来剥夺我投票的权利
by making me stand in the hallway.
其次  你应该查一查议事程序
And second, you should check the by laws.
你需要先发通知  然后至少一个工作日之后
You need notice and at least one business day
才能重新考虑同一项提议
before you can reconsider any matter.
我们将要表决的是不同的提议
We're voting on a different matter,
你有利益冲突  需要回避
which you are conflicted out of.
我怎么会有利益冲突
How can I be conflicted?
投票将决定是否开除詹姆斯·威尔森医生
This vote is whether to dismiss Dr. James Wilson.
内奥米拒绝剖腹产
Naomi is refusing to have the C-section.
她活命的机率不容乐观
Her odds aren't good enough.
这夫妻两真没用  威尔森在哪儿
They do suck. Where's Wilson?
呼他两次了
Paged him twice.
她知道自己活不成  还要这么做
She does this, she knows she's gonna die.
她是想救她的孩子
She's saving her child.
卡梅隆在的话会告诉你们
Cameron would point out
人类多么有牺牲精神
that people are capable of sacrifice.
卡梅隆可不在这儿
Cameron isn't here.
刚好证明了她的观点
Perhaps proving her point.
你觉得这女人的决定理智吗
You think this woman is making a rational decision?
我相信人可以战胜自己的本能
I think people can overcome their baser drives.
这种人稀罕的可怜
Pretty damn rarely.
而且这次不是  这是纯生物性的
And not this time. This is purely biological.
从进化的角度看
In evolutionary terms,
生下一代比较重要
the needs of the next generation are more important.
你觉得她做了正确的决定
You're saying she's making the right call?
达尔文觉得  我不
Darwin is. I'm not.
下一代不关我的事
The next generation is not my patient.
我们要提高妈妈的生存几率
We have to raise the odds for Mommy.
威尔森跑哪去了  他可是肿瘤专家
Where the hell is Wilson? He's the oncologist.
好主意  治愈癌症
Good plan. Cure cancer.
我真奇怪怎么以前没人想到
I'm surprised no one ever thought of that before.
他在那儿
There he is.
豪斯医生
Dr. House.
-你们越狱了吗  -保释了
- You guys bust out? - We made bail.
他们不让我们见宝宝
They won't let us in our baby's room.
不可思议啊
Weird.
他们正琢磨着你俩是不是想杀了孩子
You think they'd let you take her home
你说人家还会让你们带她回家吗
while they figured out if you tried to kill her.
我们是合格的父母  她一饿我们就喂她
We're good parents. We fed her whenever she was hungry.
大餐  我们不知道那食谱那么糟糕
Big meals. We had no idea that diet was so bad.
营养专家说那里面有她需要的所有东西
The nutritionist said it had everything she needed.
听着  在你所谓的健康食品店里
Listen. The kid who stacks the free-range grapefruit in
摆放有机柚子的小子可不是营养专家
your health food store is not a nutritionist.
可我叔叔真的是
But my uncle is.
他大学学的就是这个
He went to college and everything.
福曼  帮我预约断层扫描  患者为...
Foreman, I need a C.T. Scan on--
奥利弗·卡普兰
Olive Kaplan.
没开玩笑
Seriously?
奥利弗·卡普兰
Olive Kaplan.
检查有没有脓肿或是隐性感染  对
Look for abscesses or occult infections. Yeah.
拜拜
Bye-bye.
找你有事  沃格勒对临床试验一头的劲
Listen. Vogler's all about clinical trials.
医院快被他的试验噎死了
The hospital's chock full of them.
其中肯定有什么是关小细胞肺癌的
There's gotta be something for small-cell lung cancer.
你做什么
What are you doing?
我被解雇了
I got sacked.
你和卡迪调情了吗
Did you make a pass at Cuddy?
不是告诉过你吗  她只对我有性趣
I told you. She only has thighs for me.
我投票留下你
I voted to keep you.
所以他是在除掉每个想我留下的
So he's getting rid of every board member
董事会成员
who votes to keep me around.
是啊  每一个
Yeah. Every one of us.
-只有你一个  -对
- Just you? - Yep.
你只是离开董事会  对吧
But you're only off the board, right?
他们不可能一致通过开除你
They couldn't have gotten unanimous approval for you.
肿瘤科的布朗投了反对票  卡迪也是
Brown from oncology voted no. So did Cuddy,
加上泰勒和百威
Taylor and Peavey.
恩  这么看你只是离开董事会
Oh, so you're off the board.
有什么呀
Big deal.
星期三晚上解放了可以打保龄
Frees up Wednesday nights for bowling.
你还是个医生嘛
You're still a doctor.
是啊  被开除太棒了都能上名人录了
Yeah. Getting dumped looks great in Who's Who.
沃格勒让我主动辞职
Vogler gave me the option of resigning.
我接受了
And I took it.
-他可真够大方  -我没有孩子
- Big of him. - I got no kids.
我的婚姻就是个悲剧
My marriages sucks.
我仅有的两样有意义的东西
I only had two things that worked for me.
就是这个工作和这份该死的友谊
This job and this stupid screwed-up friendship,
结果这两样你都满不在乎
and neither mattered enough to you
让你做一次无聊的演讲都不行
to give one lousy speech.
我在乎
They matter.
-如果能重来...  -你还会这么做
- If I could do it all again - You'd do the same thing.
算了...你也快要走了
Well, you'll be gone soon too.
那临床试验的事
Those clinical trials?
我会打电话问问
I'll make some calls.
谢谢
Thanks.
这  这不是癌症
It's-- It's not cancer.
不会要我命吗
It's not gonna kill me?
只是痔疮
It's hemorrhoids.
可那么多血  我觉得肯定不正常
But all that blood-- I mean, that can't be right.
看起来严重而已
Looks worse than it is.
-谢谢你保护我  -能等会吗
- Nice job of protecting me. - Can this wait?
他的屁股可以等
His ass can wait.
你为了保住我开除威尔森
You save my job by sacking Wilson?
一开口就乱嚷嚷
What did you think would happen
当时你脑子里在想什么
when you made that speech?
以为随便发顿脾气
That you would just pout for a little while
我们都会原谅你的吗
and we'd all forgive you?
他是出钱的老板  哪个像你这样招惹他
You don't spit on the man that signs your paycheck.
首先是卡梅隆  接着是威尔森
First Cameron, then Wilson.
下一个就是你  穿上你的裤子
You're next. Pull your pants up.
难道都是因为钱
So it's about the money.
当然是因为钱
Of course it's about the money.
沃格勒出的钱
The money Vogler gave,
他本可以拿去买几架喷气飞机
he could have bought a few jets,
或者一支棒球队
maybe a baseball team.
或者存进大通银行坐收利息
Or just stuck it in Chase Manhattan and collected interest.
但他选择给我们买仪器  做试验
But he gave it to us to buy equipment, to do research.
你是个好医生
You are a great doctor, House,
可你不值一亿美金
but you are not worth a hundred million dollars.
我们做了肿瘤细胞DNA测序
We've sequenced the D.N.A. Of the tumor cells.
P53基因的第55位密码子发生突变
P53 gene mutation at codon 55.
她的情况完全符合你的实验条件
She's perfect for your trial.
有难度  她的癌症已经很晚期了
Hmm. She's pretty far advanced.
你想要简单的话  你选错行了
Well, you want easy cases, you picked the wrong specialty.
-病人其它身体条件好吗  -相当不错
- Otherwise in good health? - Excellent.
-她什么时候能开始  -下周三或周四
- When can she start? - Middle of next week.
癌细胞已经在第三期了
Cancer's already stage III.
-快没时间了  -两天之后开始
- It'd be a waste of time. - She can start in two days.
她两天之后不能参与试验  她怀孕了
She can't start in two days. She's pregnant.
过两天她就不怀孕了
She won't be in two days.
我预约了剖腹产
I've scheduled a C-section.
那她也要再等一个月
She'd still have to wait a month.
大手术后三十天内
You can't take part in any trial
不能参与任何临床试验
for at least 30 days after major surgery.
好吧  那绝对是个手术  不过大小嘛
Well, it's definitely surgery, but major?
-这不是你说了算的  -还是
- It's not your call. - Again,
理解不同而已
question of interpretation.
你现在开始欺骗医生了
You're scamming a doctor? Now?
拜托  沃格勒正在四处寻找解雇你的借口
Come on. Vogler's looking for any excuse to can you.
噢  估计他已经找到一大袋了
Oh, I think he's got a big bag of those already.
规例不是要和你作对才定的
These regulations aren't just here to annoy you.
你那么做对病人有危险
Doing this is dangerous to the patient.
放心  我一定会告诉她的
Well, I'll be sure and let her know that.
跟我一起来吗
Care to join me?
血管生成抑制剂
Angiogenesis inhibitors
可以阻止肿瘤生成新的血管
prevent the tumors from creating blood vessels.
没有血液供应  肿瘤会饿死
Without blood, the tumor starves.
-听起来不错  -孩子呢
- That sounds great.- What about the baby?
这种治疗对孩子是致命的
The treatment would be fatal to the baby.
我给你预约了今天下午的剖腹产
I've scheduled a C-section for this afternoon.
不要
No.
这种方法目前还在试验阶段
It's in the trial phase right now,
不过迄今在超过30%的癌症患者得到缓解
but so far complete remission in more than 30% of subjects.
我告诉过福曼医生我不做剖腹产
I told Dr. Foreman I didn't want a C-section.
到时你活下来的几率
When your chances of living
会不到现在的三分之一
were less than a third of what they are now.
如果孩子早产  那么
Well, if the baby's premature, then
我们医院儿科
Our Pediatrics Department
有本州最先进的新生儿加护病房
has the best neonatal I.C.U. in the state.
不  他的肺  他的大脑  他没准备好
No. His lungs. His brain. He's not ready.
但他会没事的
And he could be fine.
你不懂抚养一个生病的孩子的艰辛
You don't know what it's like raising a sick child.
孩子的存活几率比你的大多了
His odds are much better than yours are.
起码让他们试试看
You have to let them at least try this.
-劝劝她  -好的
- Talk to her. - Okay.
离开房间
Leave the room.
好的
Okay.
你服用奥昔布宁多久了
How long have you been taking oxybutynin?
大概从20岁开始
Uh, since I was about 20.
你这个年纪的女性小便失禁很少见
Incontinence is pretty uncommon in a woman of your age.
20岁小便失禁就更神奇了
It's even more bizarre in a woman in her 20s.
我想在健康方面
I guess I haven't had the best luck
我总能中头彩
when it comes to my health.
看来是的
Seems that way.
你刚才对你丈夫说
You said to your husband,
"你不懂抚养一个生病的孩子的艰辛"
"You don't know what it's like raising a sick child".
而不是  "你不懂得会是怎样的"
You didn't say, "You don't know what it would be like".
这不是你的第一个孩子  对吧
This is not your first child, is it?
而他不知情
And he doesn't know.
那时我18岁
I was 18.
我怀孕了  结婚了
I got pregnant, got married.
我有了世上最美丽的小女孩  格蕾丝
I had the most beautiful little girl. Grace.
她得了婴儿型亚历山大病
She had infantile Alexander's disease.
很抱歉
I'm sorry.
两年里我们看着她慢慢死去
Two years we watched her die.
我丈夫...我前夫是个
My husband was a-- Uh, my first husband was a--
很好的男人
a great guy,
但那之后我甚至没法面对他
but after that I couldn't even look at him
一看他我就想起女儿
without thinking of her.
我离开了他
I left him.
离开了我的工作  离开了一切
I left my job. I left everything.
很感人的故事
Very moving story.
难怪你这么自私
Explains why you're being so selfish.
我愿意为我丈夫去死
I'm willing to die to protect my husband.
因为那是你想要的
Because it's what you want.
你的丈夫想要的是你活下去
Your husband wants you to live.
当然  他不理解
Well, he doesn't understand
谁能理解
Oh, who the hell does?
悲剧总在上演
Tragedies happen.
如果你觉得接下来几周里
If you think that turning yourself
把自己变成个一次性育儿器
into a disposable incubator for a few weeks
就能保护你的宝宝
is gonna protect your baby
远离这个世界的烦恼
from all the crap in this world,
继续  祝你死得愉快
go ahead. Die happy.
我才不管自己找死的人
I got no problem with people killing themselves.
但别觉得那么做你会是个英雄
But don't think it makes you a hero.
好吧
Okay.
你今天下午4点剖腹产
You're scheduled for 4:00 p.M.
是  我是林医生
Yes. This is Dr. Lim.
从10开始倒数
Count down from 10.
好的
Okay.
十
Ten,
九
nine,
八...
eight
托盘准备好了
Tray setup.
好像有点快  她还好吧
That seemed kind of fast. Is she all right?
她很好
She's fine.
叫醒她  沃格勒的电话  手术取消
Wake her up. That was Vogler. Surgery is off.
嘿  你会害死她
Hey! You're killing her!
是吗  手术后才五分钟
Really? I thought you were the one trying
就给她做药物实验  是你想要她的命吧
to ram her into a drug trial five minutes after surgery.
她知道危险性  她是完全知情的
She knows the risk. She was fully informed.
但做实验的人肯定不知情
Well, the guy running the study sure wasn't.
不是他的命  不由他做主
Not his life. Not his call.
-他的实验  他做主  -是啊
- His study, his call. - Right.
她若死了  实验数据就不好
So she kicks off, his numbers look bad.
数据不好  实验就效果就差
The numbers look bad, the study looks bad.
还要费你很多钱是吗
Which would cost you money!
还妨碍了一个救生办法的问世
And keep a lifesaving protocol off the market.
一条命  只是数据上的一个点
One person! One blip in the data!
知道食品药物管理局吗  他们就盯着坏点
Ever heard of the F.D.A.? They eat blips for breakfast.
不能因一个人而害了千万条命
One person should never endanger thousands.
多谢你这个救世主来挽救众生
Well, thank God you were here to save all those lives!
今晚将再开董事会
The board's meeting again this evening.
你为何不舒服的坐着  玩玩掌上游戏
Why don't you settle down, play some Game Boy?
再看看肥皂剧
Why don't you watch your soap?
听说这集今天要炒掉那个帅哥医生
I hear they're firing the handsome doctor today.
兄弟  那可是场好戏
Boy, that should be a good one.
不论如何  若做了剖腹产
If we had the C-section anyway,
她还是可以进行实验性治疗  对吧
she could still do the experimental treatment, right?
-我们只需等一个月  -假若
- We'd just have to wait 30 days. - Assuming
负责实验的医生没有愤怒到拒绝接收她
the doctor running the trial isn't too pissed off to let her in.
还得我撑得住才行
And assuming I'm even healthy enough to--
亲爱的
Honey.
你还好吧
Are you okay?
血氧下降到80  挺住  内奥米
Sats are dropping down to the 80s. Stay with us, Naomi.
-怎么回事  -请你离开病房
- What's going on? - We need you to leave the room.
呼吸窘迫
Respiratory distress.
能告诉我怎么回事吗
Could you tell me what's going on?
我们正在努力查找
We're trying to find out.
-这里  -还在跳动
- Here.  - Still kicking.
急性肺水肿
Flash pulmonary edema?
肺野透亮  找到了
Lungs are clear. Here it is.
-肺水肿  -得马上送手术室
- Pulmonary embolus. - Gotta get her to an O.R.
-立刻  赶紧  -发生什么事了
- Now. Right away.  - Uh, what happened?
是血栓
It's an embolism-a blood clot.
肺癌常见症
Fairly common with lung cancer.
不是完全性癌栓堵塞
It's not a full saddle embolism.
血液还能流通
So blood's still trickling through.
我们已经让她有了点呼吸
We've been able to get Naomi breathing a little,
但还得除掉血栓
but we need to remove the clot,
需要你同意治疗
and we need you to approve the treatment.
当然
Of course.
不管你们要做什么  做就是了
Whatever you have to do, just do it.
没那么简单
It's not that simple.
对婴儿来说最好是马上做剖腹产
The best course for the baby would be an immediate C-section.
拖得越久
The longer we postpone,
他的脑部由于缺氧而受损的可就越大
the greater chance he'll have brain damage from lack of oxygen.
行  那就做吧
Fine. Just do it.
问题是
Here's the problem.
剖腹产对内奥米会非常危险
The C-section would be very very dangerous for Naomi.
有多危险
Dangerous like--
就她目前的状况
In her current condition,
很可能会丧命
there's a real chance she won't survive.
抱歉
I'm sorry.
你妻子已经昏迷  需要你来做决定
Your wife's unconscious. We need you to make a decision.
我只要她活着
I just want her to live.
不做剖腹产
No C-section.
血氧还在下降  得给她打溶栓酶
Sats are still way down. We gotta push the streptokinase.
太危险了  就算血栓被溶解
Too risky. Even if it dissolves the clot,
她还是可能会出血
she could still bleed out--
她的血液循环动力受到影响
She's hemodynamically compromised.
那对婴儿不好
It's not good for the baby.
孩子父亲不在乎
Dad doesn't care.
注射造影剂250，000个单位
Bolusing 250,000 units.
血压在下降
B.P.'s dropping.
-加压  -没时间了  必须吸出血栓
- Pressors.  - Don't have time. We've gotta suck it out.
心缩压80
Systolic B.P.'s 80.
血压稳定了
B.P.'s stabilizing.
血氧量上升
O2 sats rising.
-清除血栓了吗  -是的
- Did you get the clot? - I think so.
她的状况稳定了
She's stabilized.
她的血氧在那个阶段持续了多久
How long was her oxygen at that level?
-大概10分钟  -大脑功能有没受损
- About 10 minutes. - Brain function compromised?
应该没有  但我们会
Shouldn't be, but we'll--
血压在下降  加大多巴胺的剂量
B.P.'s dropping. Up the dopamine.
没反应  到多少了
She's not responding. How much?
30微克了
Up to 30 micrograms.
难道是败血吗
Is she septic?
她腹内出血
She's bleeding into her abdomen.
我们无法阻止
We won't be able to stop it.
我去和她丈夫谈谈
I'll go talk to the husband.
不  你待在这里
No. You stay here.
尽力让她保持稳定  越久越好
Keep her as stable as you can for as long as you can.
手术途中她受到损伤
She had trauma during the procedure.
血在流向腹部
She's bleeding into her abdomen.
我们已无能为力了  抱歉
There's nothing we can do. I'm sorry.
哦  不
Oh. No.
你必须同意做剖腹产
I need you to okay the C-section.
那会要了她的命  是吧
That's gonna kill her, right?
可能会
Probably will.
我不同意
I can't do that.
她还是会死
She's dying either way.
-对  对不起  -冷静点  肖恩
- I'm-- I'm sorry. - Stay with me,Sean
你必须同意
I need your okay on this.
那是她的决定  我
She makes the decisions, and I'm--
是  从现在起情况很紧急
Right. And that's gonna be tough from now on,
但做这个决定很简单
but this decision is easy.
-你知道她想要什么吧  -知道
- You know what she'd want.  - Yeah.
我办不到
I can't do
你做了这个决定  能改变两件事
You make this call, only two things change.
第一  没错  你会为害了你妻子而内疚
One, yeah, you feel guilty for killing your wife.
但第二  你们的孩子能活下来
Two, your baby lives.
内奥米的孩子能活下来
Naomi's baby lives.
好  好吧
Okay. Okay.
出来了  脐带已剪断
He's out. Umbilical cord's clamped.
-没呼吸  -他的肺还没打开
- No respiration.  - His lungs aren't opening up.
它们还没发育完全
They aren't mature.
加油  呼吸啊  你行的
Come on. Take a breath. You know you can do it.
怎么了
What you got?
-像是室颤  -脉搏
- Looks like V-fib.  - Pulse?
-停止了  电击板  -这里
- No. Paddles.  - Right here.
加油  加油
Come on. Come on.
离手
Clear!
-没反应  -充电
- Nothing.  - Charging.
乖孩子  张嘴呼吸啊
Good boy. Open up.
他怎么样
How's he doin'?
还是没呼吸  需要插管
Still not breathing. We've gotta intubate.
完毕
Clear!
谢谢
Thank you.
-董事会我已经迟到了  -我们得谈谈
- I'm late for the board meeting.  - We need to talk.
-我不想听  -是有关一个病人的
- I don't want to hear it.  - It's about a patient.
那个孕妇
The pregnant woman?
她不能参与实验
She wasn't qualified for that trial.
-我不会道歉的  -我不是说她
- And I'm not gonna apologize - I'm not talking about her.
在这个节骨眼上
At this point,
我最好还是把精力放在那些还活着的病人上
I think it's best if I concentrate on patients who are still alive.
肺气肿  她大出血  只救了她儿子
Pulmonary embolism. She bled out. Saved her son.
这是奥利弗·卡普兰的CT
This is Olive Kaplan's C.T. scan
那个可怜的小婴儿
The incredible shrinking baby.
她的胸腺
Her thymus gland.
先天性胸腺发育不全综合症  是遗传的
DiGeorge syndrome. It's genetic.
导致胸腺萎缩得几乎没了
Caused the gland to wither to nothing.
-所以她才不能增重  -是的
- This is why she couldn't gain weight.  - Yeah.
我会给警察和社会福利部门打电话
I'll call the police and Social Services
撤回所有控诉
and have all the charges withdrawn.
我开了检查单子去确认  等结果出来
I've sent a test down to confirm. When it comes back,
你就给奥利弗做免疫球蛋白替代治疗
you should start Olive on immunoglobulin replacement.
你不自己做吗
You're not gonna do it?
我想到时我已不在这里了
Well, I assume I won't be here.
你儿子很好
Your boy is doing good.
和昨天一样的提议  各位
It's the same motion as yesterday, people.
一样的理由
Same reasons.
同意开除格利高里·豪斯的
All those in favor of dismissing Gregory House,
请举手
raise a hand.
卡迪医生
Dr. Cuddy,
你得明白这是必然的
you realize this is going to happen.
-我做不到  -你不能弃权
- I can't do it.  - You can't abstain.
不是弃权  我是反对
I'm not abstaining. I'm voting no.
才一天你就改变主意啦
You've changed your mind since yesterday?
他做了什么
What did he do?
请你吃饭  送玫瑰给你
Buy you dinner and roses?
威胁要杀了你的狗
Threaten to drown your dog?
-他尽到了职责  -是啊
- He did his job.  - Right.
他又救了一条生命
He saved another life.
-也许  -他真厉害
- Maybe. - Good for him.
真伟大  但不能说明问题
It's great. It's not the point.
那是我们的工作
It's what we do.
如果不用担心某个疯子会
And you could do it a lot better
在医院四处乱晃且不听命于任何人
if you didn't have to worry about some madman...
你可以做的更好
running around the hospital accountable to no one.
但那不是你给我们的选择
But that's not the choice you're giving us.
豪斯不会服从于任何人
House won't listen to anyone.
你也一样是独断专行
And you're not accountable to anybody either.
因为你觉得我们归你所有
Because you think you own us.
我提议立即开除丽莎·卡迪医生
I move for the immediate dismissal of Dr. Lisa Cuddy.
她只是情绪低落  我们都是
She's upset. We all are.
你为什么要牺牲自己的事业来保全他
Why would you risk your career to save him?
如果你们觉得豪斯应该离开
If you think House deserves to go,
觉得我应该离开
if you think I deserve to go,
威尔森应该离开  尽管举手就是了
Wilson deserved to go, then vote yes.
但若你们是出于
But if you're doing this because
害怕失去他的钱而赞同他
you are afraid of losing his money, then he's right.
那你们真是归他所有
He does own you.
你们还有选择权
You have a choice.
这可能是你们最后一个选择权
Maybe the last real one you'll have here.
卡迪是个天才
Cuddy is a genius.
说服了四个人放弃
Convincing four people to give up
一大笔钱来保住我们的饭碗
a fortune to save our sorry asses.
-卡迪医生  伟大的女英雄
- Dr. Cuddy, the man of the hour.
你们在做什么
What are you doing?
喝酒啊
We're drinking.
这不是很明显吗
I would have thought that was pretty obvious.
庆祝伟大的胜利  救了你
To the great champion. Saved you,
救了威尔森  救了整个团队
saved Wilson-- saved the whole team.
当然  如果你能好好和别人相处的话
Of course none of them would have needed saving
这一切都可以避免
if you could actually get along with another human being.
多谢  扫兴女王
Thank you, Miss Buzz Kill.
你只不过花了我们一亿美元嘛
Well, you only cost us a hundred million dollars.
本可以用来救几条命
Could have saved some lives,
提供几份工作  帮助一些人
could have made a few jobs, helped a few people-- yippee.
你还是选择让他走
You voted to get rid of him.
两害相权取其轻
The lesser of two evils.
你该感到哀痛
You should be mourning.
至少我是
I know I am.